the Declaration would be issued on July
26th
1945 however after the first day there
was still no response even after the
second day and then the third there was
still no response the Allies would hear
nothing under the leadership of prime
minister Suzuki the Japanese considering
the terms of the potam Declaration
unacceptable and still unwilling to
surrender had chosen to enact a policy
of mock satsu or killing with silence
deciding to ignore the ultimatum
altogether
to the Japanese giving no response at
all was in fact a response it was a
complete dismissal of the terms this
would leave Truman with very few options
he would now have to consider using the
atomic bomb with many factors Weighing
on his mind